Mahmut Taskiran

Android & Cross Mobile Application Developer

github.com/mahmuttaskiran | linkedin.com/in/mahmutaskiran | mamudo.com | +90 546 227 2550 taskiranmahmutt@gmail.com

SUMMARY

I am a professional programmer specialized mobile applications and tools. I have been developing Android native applications with Java and Kotlin, and cross-platform applications with Flutter and React-Native. I have experience developing social media applications (with React-Native and Flutter), IoT applications (with Flutter and Java), sensor-based applications (with Java), WebRTC based applications (with React-Native).

I am learning new and innovator programming languages and paradigms just like Rust even if I don't work any related project with it. I have been focused on developing my programming skills rather than learning a new programming language. Because I believe that programming is a thinking art, so if I improve my programming knowledge then I can think better.

CORE COMPETENCIES

Java, Kotlin, Android SDK, Flutter, React-Native, Git, Go, Rust and JavaScript.

EXPERIENCES

ARGELOJI, Istanbul Turkey - Mobile Application Developer, Project Leader

June 2019 - July 2020

I have been developed BlueOperation's mobile application for Argeloji. BlueOperation offers RTLS solutions that can actively monitor the location of assets to optimize searching time in a wide range of area facilities such as Airports.

www.argeloji.com

www.blueoperation.io

play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.blueoperation_mobile

POLYINGO (Mobile Application) - Full Stack Mobile Application Developer

July 2019 - October 2020

Polyingo is a language learning application written in Flutter. It's available on the PlayStore and AppStore.

play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.polyingo www.polyingo.com

CEKIRDEK BILGISAYAR, Istanbul Turkey - Mobile Application Developer

July 2017 - May 2018

Used Kotlin and Android Framework to develop social networking applications. Worked with React-Native to re-write some applications written in PhoneGAP. cekirdekbilgisayar.com.tr

OPCON (Mobile Application) - Full Stack Mobile Application Developer

April 2016- October 2017

Open source Android application written in Java. It is my first application that I developed for Android individually.

github.com/mahmuttaskiran/Opcon

EDUCATION

2012-2016 Bachelor's Degree | Ege University | Radio Television and Cinema
2017-2019 Associate Degree | Anadolu University | Web Design and Programming
2020-2024 Bachelor's Degree | Anadolu University | Information Management Systems

LANGUAGES

Turkish (Native), English (Professional)